Part 1. You will hear an interviewer who is doing a survey asking a man some questions
about shopping. First, you have some time to look at questions 1 to 6.
Now listen carefully and answer questions 1 to 6.
Good morning. I'm doing a survey of shoppers in Broadbeach. Would you have a few minutes
to spare to answer some questions? Oh, um, yes, I guess it would be OK.
Thank you very much. Everybody seems so busy today.
Well, actually, I don't have loads of time, so...
Oh, yes, of course. It really won't take long. Could I start by taking your name, please?
I'm Lee. Martins with a Y. And is your family name spelt L-double-E?
It's L-E-I-G-H. Thank you. We don't actually publish your
name or details. It just makes it easier for me to identify people when I look at all the
results at the end. I see.
And can I ask, how did you get into town today? Well, normally I catch the bus, but I'm on
my motorbike today because I'm going to work later.
And could you tell me what you're doing this morning? I mean, the reason for your trip
into town? Well, I've just been to the hairdresser. You
see, I have a job interview at the council in a few days.
Oh, really? Well, good luck with that. Thanks a lot. And now I'm on my way to buy
a suit that I can wear to the interview. I don't actually own one at the moment.
OK. Is that everything you're planning to do in town?
Yeah. Well, I've got to go and pick up my laptop. It broke a couple of days ago, so
I took it to the shop to get it fixed. They had to order a spare part, but apparently
it's ready for collection now. I can't wait to get it back.
I'm sure. I hate it when my technology breaks down. One more thing. It's Saturday today.
Is that when you like to do your shopping? Well, it's more of a question of when I'm
free. If I'm free on a Monday, that's when I choose to come into town. The shops are
less busy then, which I always prefer.
Now listen and answer questions 7 to 10.
So I'd like to ask you a few more questions to get your views about shopping in Broad
Beach, if that's OK? Sure. What would you like to know specifically?
What would you say you like best about the shops here?
I'd probably say it's the service you get wherever you go.
OK. And what do you think about the range of shops in Broad Beach?
Oh, you can get almost anything you want here. And what about recent changes? What do you
like and dislike about them? For example, there are a lot of new coffee shops now. Are
you enjoying them? No, there are too many of them. It's a shame
as those places could be occupied by other kinds of shops.
What would you like to see instead? Well, I think we have enough clothing shops,
but there's only one place that sells books at the moment. It'd be nice to have a choice,
you know. Right. And have you been to the new shopping
centre outside Broad Beach yet, Martin? Yes, once or twice. It's not that far from
where I live. It's a very modern-looking building, isn't
it? Yes, and it's lovely. The glass roof is certainly
impressive, but my favourite thing is the plants they've put round the building. They're
amazing and so big already. And what about the entertainment facilities?
Have you used any of them yet? Like the new cinema?
Nah, not yet. I can't see any advantage in having it there because the one in town is
actually bigger. OK. Well, thank you so much for your time.